{
    "data":[
    { "id":11,
      "question":"What is a socket?",
      "answer":"Socket is a combination of port + ip + protocol. Sockets allow communication between two processes on the same or different hosts that are connected by internet.",
      "link":""
    },
    { "id":12,
      "question":"How many IPS are there is 10.28.0.0/16 CIDR?",
      "answer":"This will be 2^32-16 IP which is 2^16 = 65536",
      "link":""
    },
    { "id":13,
      "question":"Which port dns works on?",
      "answer":"53",
      "link":""
    },
    { "id":14,
      "question":"Dns uses which protocol?",
      "answer":"udp",
      "link":""
    },
    { "id":15,
      "question": "Can DNS work on tcp?",
      "answer":"Yes, but it will be slow which is not expection from dns.",
      "link":""
    },
    { "id":16,
        "question": "IP(Internet Protocol) is a reliable protocol, True or false? ",
        "answer":"False. It is best effort delivery",
        "link":""
    },
    { "id":17,
        "question": "What adds reliability to the TCP or why you say tcp is a reliable protocol?",
        "answer":"First it does 3 way handshake to the host, next it has mechanism of retries and acknowledgement that adds reliability to it.",
        "link":""
    },
    { "id":18,
        "question": "How can you keep a watch on out put of command?",
        "answer":"watch `command`",
        "link":""
    },
    { "id":19,
        "question": "Where are the logs generally kept?",
        "answer":"You can find them in /var/log but its not sure to always be here. It can depend on applications where they want to keep the logs.",
        "link":""
    },
    { "id":20,
        "question": "In which file you can configure what nameserver to use to resolve your dns queries?",
        "answer":"In /etc/resolv.conf, you specify these settings.",
        "link":""
    }
  ]
}
  
